Remember the "Personality".
牢記人格
No murder, O.K?
冇有謀殺，好嗎？
Let's pray.
讓我們祈禱吧
- Dad? - Zuhal?
-爸爸？-祖哈爾？
- Did you know Mr.Tayfun? - Of Course I did.
-你認識泰豐先生嗎？-我當然認識
All the way from Kambura.
在坎佈拉時就認識他
Sorry for your loss.
節哀
Be brave son. You can't escape fate.
堅強起來孩子  冇有人能逃過命運
What fate? They blew up the flower man.
什麼命運？他們把花匠炸死了
As founders of the "Dog Killer" Fan Club we officially welcome you.
作為“狗殺手”粉絲俱樂部的創始人，我們正式歡迎你
If you don't make an arrest within a week, it's over.
如果一周之內抓不到他，那就結束了
The girl whom Tayyar raped...
被塔亞爾強姦的女孩
she is talking to me. Look what she's saying.
她在跟我說話  看看她說的
Help me Nevra.
救救我內芙拉
Up until now, I have been her voice.
直到現在，她一直在嚮我傾訴
All these murders are for her revenge.
所有這些謀殺都是為了報仇
If we find her we find this one too.
如果我們找到她，我們也找到這個兇手
We have to go to Kambura immediately.
我們必須立即去坎佈拉
Ladies, anyone who was raped or sexually abused...
女士們，任何遭受過性虐待或強奸的人……
please call this number.
請打這個電話
What do you mean by "they gathered the women"?
“他們把女人們聚集起來”是什麼意思？
She is trying to find the girl who was raped by Tayyar.
她試圖找到被塔亞爾強奸的女孩
O.K, just stand by. I'll think of something.
好吧，你待命  我要想一想
They checked out the burned house.
他們檢查了燒毀的房子
Find a bulldozer immediately.
馬上找一臺推土機
And knock it down.
把房子拆掉
- I don't recognize the number. - Go on, answer it.
-一個陌生號碼 -快接
Hello?
餵？
Just tell me everything from the beginning.
從頭說起  把一切都告訴我
It was an ordinary day. I had just finished my grocery shopping.
那是很平常的一天  我剛在雜貨店買完東西
As I left the shop Tayyar appeared out of nowhere.
我離開商店時，塔亞爾突然出現
He grabbed me and...
他抓住了我……
you know, in the woods.
然後，在樹林裏……
She remembers everything.
她記得一切
Just call me if you need anything.
有什麼需要就打給我
Thank you very much. You don't need to hang around.
非常感謝  你不必在這裏等的
Firuz...
菲魯茲
the less you know, the better you can sleep at night.
你知道得越少  晚上睡得越香
Then you won't have to call me...
那樣的話你就不會打電話給我了
or say "leave me alone".
或者說“別管我”
Do you think Nevra was convinced?
你認為內芙拉被說服了嗎？
Absolutely.
絕對的
She was about to start crying, thanks to my story-telling skill.
我講故事的技巧很好，她都快要哭了
By the way, I talked to Cemil. He said you have the rest of my money.
順便說一句，我跟塞米爾談過  他說我的錢在你這裏
Yes, that's right.
是的，在這
- S..it! - What is it?
-媽的！-什麼？
So much for been convinced.
你還說服了呢
She is following us.
她在跟著我們
- Where? - Don't turn around.
-在哪裏？-不要轉身
What are we going to do now?
我們現在要做什麼？
S..it!
媽的！
What am I going to do now?
我現在該怎麼辦？
What now?
現在怎麼辦？
Think. Where is your home?
想想你的家在哪裏？
Think, think, think.
想，想，想
Where is your house?
你的房子在哪裏？
No, it's not going to work.
不，這行不通
Mrs Feza!
費紮夫人！
Let's go.
我們走吧
Come on, get up. Let's go.
來吧，起來吧  我們走
Get up. I don't know where but we should go.
站起來，我不知道該去哪裏，但我們該走了
Here you go.
幹得好
My bag...
我的包……
anything else?
還有別的嗎？
O.K, this way Mrs Feza. Here you go.
好的，走這邊  是的
Is she still following you?
她還在跟著你嗎？
Keep going Firuz.
不要停下 菲魯茲
Don't get out the car until I think of something, O.K?
在我想到解決方案之前不要下車  明白嗎？
Mrs Feza!
費紮夫人！
I've read thousands of novels and I decided to write one myself.
我讀過數仟本小說，所以我決定自己寫一個
And you two f..cked it up.
但是你們兩個都搞砸了
-Listen to me now. -I am listening Mr.Cemil.
-現在聽我說  -我在聽  塞米爾先生
- Can you hear me Yeliz? - Yes, I can.
-你能聽到我說話嗎？耶利茲  -是的，我可以
I made some calls. We'll change the story a little.
我打了幾個電話  我們將改變這個故事
What I'm about to say, get it into your heads.
我要說的是，把它記在腦子裏
Smallest mistake, you're done with.
哪怕犯一個小錯誤  你就完了
Hello?
餵？
Are you serious?
你是認真的嗎？
Yeliz met with Firuz? There must be a mistake.
耶利茲與菲魯茲見麵？一定有什麼誤會吧
No mistake. They are right ahead of me.
冇有誤會  他們就在我前麵
It is obvious that they know each other. He is driving her somewhere.
很明顯，他們彼此認識  他現在正開車帶她去什麼地方
O.K. Hang on a minute. Just calm down.
好  等一下  冷靜一下
Do you mean Yeliz was bulls... tting you last night?
你是說耶利茲昨晚在跟你扯淡嗎？
And now, she is with Firuz, right?
現在，她和菲魯茲在一起，對嗎？
Yes, that's exactly so.
是的，就是這樣
I have to talk to Firuz to find out what's been happening.
我必須和菲魯茲談談這到底是怎麼回事
Just hang up.
先掛了
Don't call him now Sefer. I have to see where they are headed.
現在別打給他  塞法  我必須看看他們要去哪裏
Listen to me. No one knows Firuz better than I do.
聽我說  冇有人比我更了解菲魯茲
If there is something iffy going on, either he won't answer...
如果有什麼不愉快的事情，他也不會接
or give me a lot of crap.
也不會跟我說廢話
I have to call Firuz to find out.
我必須打電話給菲魯茲找出答案
- Hang on a minute. - What?
-等一下-什麼？
Are you going to tell him that I've been following him?
你會告訴他我一直在跟著他嗎？
If I know Firuz well enough, he already figured out that he's being followed.
以我對菲魯茲的了解，他已經知道了自己在被跟蹤
No, it is not here either.
不，也不在這裏
I made a note of everything.
我記下了一切
Even, chucking the TV set out. But no address.
甚至記錄了不喜歡電視機，但冇有地址
I am so stupid.
我好笨
Poor Agah.
可憐的阿加
Not in the wallet either.
也不在錢包裏
But it should be on the car's log book.
但這應該在汽車的日誌上
Yes, it should be on the log book.
是的，應該在日誌上
Calm down Agah.
冷靜下來  阿加
Take a deep breath.
深呼吸
Thank you.
謝謝
Take a deep breath.
深呼吸
Mrs. Feza, I don't remember where I live.
費紮夫人，我不記得我住在哪裏了
I don't remember my home.
我不記得我的家了
What the hell is going on?
這到底是怎麼回事？
Keep doing whatever you've been doing.
繼續做你一直在做的事
Excuse me?
什麼？
Keep following me. I called Sefa. He is on his way.
繼續跟著我  我叫了塞法  他在路上
We have to sit down and talk.
我們必須坐下來談談
Everything should be here.
應該都在這裏
I make a note of everything in this black book.
我把所有筆記都記在這個黑本子裏
It says here "Combination for the Flat No 8 is 1682".
上麵寫著：“ 8號公寓的密碼組合是1682”
But what is Flat No:8?
但是什麼是8號公寓？
Where the hell is it? How the hell do I know?
到底在哪裏？我怎麼知道？
Why didn't I write down the address instead of the combination?
我為什麼不寫下地址而寫了密碼組合呢？
Such an idiot!
我真是個白癡！
Unfortunately, this is the situation we are in right now.
很不幸，這就是我們現在的情況
I don't remember.
我不記得了
There must be a reason why I forgot.
一定是有原因的
I'll take you to seaside.
我帶你去海邊
I can play flamenco for you.
我可以為你演奏弗拉門戈舞
- Olé! - Yes, sure, Olé.
-奧萊！-是的，奧萊！
Remember when you asked me how the idea came up?
還記得你問我這個想法是怎麼産生的嗎？
When you said why should others decide who is to be killed?
當你說為什麼其他人要決定別人的生死時？
Do you know why?
你知道為什麼嗎？
Because they've always been the ones to decide.
因為他們一直是決定的人
Come over here.
過來
Gerome painted this in 1872.
傑羅姆在1872年畫了這幅畫
What are those people doing?
那些人在做什麼？
That's what the painting is called. "Pollice Verso".
那幅畫叫做“ Pollice Verso”
It means "thumbs down".
意思是“拇指嚮下”
And who is it for?
那是給誰畫的？
For the gladiator.
給角鬥士
Why? So he can kill this man.
為什麼？所以他可以殺了這個人
Actually, it is not clear which one means "death" in ancient Rome.
實際上，在古羅馬尚不清楚哪一個意味著“死亡”
This, or this.
這個或這個
But Gerome thought this was the fitting one.
但是傑羅姆認為這是一個合適的選擇
If you do this, the gladiator will kill.
如果這樣做，角鬥士就會殺人
And there would be death in the Arena.
競技場中將會有人死亡
If you do this you save the man's life.
如果這樣，你可以挽救人的性命
But one is not enough. The decision has to be unanimous.
但是一個人這樣做還不夠  決定必須是一緻的
What I mean is, who will die or live has to be decided unanimously.
我的意思是，生或死必須共同決定
Unanimous decisions are always deemed legitimate.
一緻的決定總是被認為是合法的
It will take the guilty conscience away.
它會帶走內疚的良心
At the end of the day, you are inciting to a murder.
歸根結底，這是煽動謀殺
It is a crime.
這是犯罪
But this way, everybody can point the finger at each other.
但是這樣，每個人都可以互相指責
And the crime disappears.
罪行就消失了
What this painting tells us that...
這幅畫告訴我們的是
if you want to commit a crime and not get blamed...
如果你想犯罪而不會受到指責
all you have to do is to build a crowd around you.
你所要做的就是在你周圍建立一個群體
It is no longer a crime, if you commit it with a large enough crowd.
如果你在足夠多的群體中進行犯罪，就不再是犯罪
And...
而且……
do these remind you anything?
這些會讓你想到什麼嗎？
Well...
嗯……
you upload a video on YouTube.
你將視訊上載到YouTube
What happens is that it is judged by people you don't even know.
發生的這些事情是由你甚至不認識的人來判斷
Like...
喜歡
and dislike.
不喜歡
Life...
生
or death.
或死
As you can see, nothing has changed in 2 thousand years Süveyda.
如你所見，兩仟多年來，一切都冇有改變  蘇薇達
Only difference is that you can't do this anymore.
唯一的區別是你不能再做拇指嚮上或嚮下的動作
You have to click on the icons.
你必須點選圖示
I thought of it when I saw the painting.
我看到畫的時候就想到了
We have the gladiator, so let the crowd decide who'll die.
我們有角鬥士，所以讓人群決定誰會死
- Did you hear it? - What?
-聽說了嗎？-什麼？
The three man who were killed?
被殺的三個人？
The ones with the word "personal" carved on their forehead?
額頭刻有“個人”的三人？
They were on the list in our website.
他們在我們網站的名單上
- Are you serious? - Why don't you check it out?
-真的嗎？-為什麼不自己看一下？
Switch on the computer Süveyda.
打開電腦  蘇薇達
I found out at school. They just told me.
我在學校知道的  他們剛剛告訴我
One of them was running a food kiosk or something.
其中一個人是經營食品亭還是什麼的
He says "they are extorting money from me. I hope the "Dog Killer" kill them all".
他說：“他們勒索我的錢，我希望“狗殺手”能把他們都殺死”
They issued the names too Only a day before the murders.
就在謀殺的前一天  他們在網站上公佈了姓名
And people went wild. Everybody is loading names on the list.
人們瘋狂起來了  每個人都在列錶上輸入名字
You know what this means don't you?
你知道這意味著什麼嗎？
"Dog Killer" is following our website.
“狗殺手”正在關註我們的網站
Alright then. What were you doing there? How do you know this woman?
好吧，那你在做什麼？你怎麼認識這個女人？
No rush. There is a time for everything. Wait till Sefa gets here.
別著急  等塞法來了再說
Here he is.
他來了
What the hell do you think you're doing?
你以為你在做什麼？
Put it this way, I have to do the s... itty work...
這樣說吧   髒活必須由我來做
because you have been so f..cking useless.
因為你一點用都冇有
- What are you talking about? - Murders are piling up every day.
-你在說什麼？-謀殺案每天都在發生
And your brains are messed up with Kambura.
你們的大腦被坎佈拉弄得一團糟
We are not getting anywhere.
我們一點頭緒都冇有
They are going mad in Ankara. And I have to take all the s... it.
安卡拉的人生氣了  我必須要做點什麼
Remember coming to the hospital yesterday?
還記得昨天去醫院嗎？
They called me straight after you left.
你離開後他們就來找我
- Who are "they"? - Ones at the top in Ankara.
-誰是“他們”？-安卡拉高層人士
They said "there is something iffy going on over there. Dig into it".
他們說“那邊有點問題  跟進一下”
I said "you want me to investigate my partners"?
我說“你是要我調查我的同事嗎？”
They said "exactly".
他們說“正是”
Yes sir.
長官好
- Does boss know about it? - They probably told him.
-老大知道嗎？-他們可能和他說了
I'll go and talk to him anyway.
反正我也要去和他談談
I have been a superintendent for years. I am not going to spy on my team.
我已經擔任主管多年了，我不會監視我的團隊
They told Chief Tolga, gave him a week.
他們告訴托爾加檢察官，給了他一周的時間
If he can't solve it they'll show him the door.
如果他解決不了，他們會讓他滾蛋
Yes sir, I understand sir.
是的，長官，我知道
Yes, you've told me sir.
是的，你已經告訴我了
But I think it is unnecessary.
但我認為這是不必要的
No.
不是
Because I trust my team sir.
因為我相信我的團隊  長官
O.K.
好
I understand.
我明白
So, what is it? Do they suspect us?
那是什麼？他們懷疑我們嗎？
Thanks.
謝謝
Don't pretend that you don't already know Sefa.
不要裝傻了  Sefa
They are just pulling the wool over eyes.
他們是在欺騙我們
They will want to justify their action when the case blows bigger...
當案情惡化時，他們想要證明自己的行為是正確的
in couple of days.
在幾天之內
They'll say "we investigated the cops."
他們會說：“我們調查了警察”
Everybody is trying to save their own a..ss.
每個人都在努力拯救自己
It is all about saving your skin.
都是為了保住官服
That's what it is.
就是這樣
Nothing beats the seaside.
冇什麼比海邊更好的了
Nothing can beat it.
冇有了
It must've been 50 years since I last flew a kite.
自從我上一次在這裏放風吹已經過去50年了
50 years at least.
至少50年
I have to run to fly it. But how can I run?
我必須奔跑才能飛起來  但是我怎麼跑？
I'll be back in a minute. Wait here.
我很快就回來  等我一下
Let me ask you something?
讓我問你一件事？
How did you figure it out?
你是如何知道的？
I mean, how did you figure out that I was going to meet the woman?
我的意思是，你如何得知我要去見那個女人？
I didn't figure out that you were going to meet.
我不知道你們會見麵
I only figured out that she was lying.
我隻知道她在撒謊
But everything she told me made sense.
但是她告訴我的一切都是有道理的
That's right, it all made sense.
是的，一切都說得通
Except one thing.
除了一件事
No man in Kambura would marry a non-virgin.
坎佈拉冇有任何一個男人會娶一個不是處女的老婆
It doesn't matter how much he loves her.
無論是否愛她
It is against Kambura's customs.
這違反了坎佈拉的習俗
That's why, the woman in question either never got raped nor she is married.
這就是為什麼這個女人既冇有被強奸過也冇有結過婚
But since we knew she was married, I decided to follow her...
但是因為我知道她已經結婚了，所以我決定跟隨她……
to find out where she was going and who was forcing her to lie.
查清楚她要去哪裏，誰在強迫她說謊
That's when you came into the scene.
那時候我就看到了你
You're doing good.
你做得很好
May be not so good.
可能不是很好
But you'll do it.
但是你會成功的
- I can't do it. - You can do it.
-我做不到-你可以的
I'll tell you what, let's try 10 more times and...
我告訴你，讓我們再嘗試10次，
we'll quit if it doesn't work out.
如果還是不行，我們就停下
Go on. This is the first. We start with the first one.
繼續  這是第一次  我們從第一次開始
Mrs. Feza.
費紮夫人
Come on.
來吧
It's O.K.
冇關係
Let's go for the second.
我們來嘗試第二次
Come on son.
來吧孩子
Well done.
做得好
No, this way.
不  這邊
Faster.
快點
Three.
第三次
For the forth time.
第四次
Lie? Why should I lie to you?
撒謊？我為什麼要騙你
If you don't believe me ask my husband.
如果你不相信我  那你去問問我的丈夫
Ask him if I was virgin when we got married.
問他我結婚時是不是處女
It's O.K Nevra.
好了 內芙拉
That's enough. We'll drop you off wherever you want to go.
夠了，我們會送你去你想去的地方
What sort of a woman are you, making me talk about such things?
你算什麼女人  讓我談論這些事情？
How can you do this to your own kind? Have you got no feelings?
你怎麼能對自己的同類做這種事情？你冇有感情嗎？
What did your mum used to say to you Yeliz?
你媽媽過去曾對你說過什麼？
What do you mean? What's that got to do with anything?
那是什麼意思？跟這有什麼關係？
What did your mum used to say to you when you were little?
你媽媽小時候對你說了什麼？
How was she threatening you?
她怎麼威脅你？
Wasn't she saying "do you want to become a whore"?
她是不是在說“你想成為妓女”嗎？
"You'll end up becoming a whore".
“你最終會變成妓女”
Isn't that what she was saying?
她冇說過嗎？
What's that got to do with anything?
那和這有什麼關係？
That's what she used say, wasn't it?
她就是這麼說的，不是嗎？
Do you know why? Because your mum knew exactly what Kambura was like.
你知道為什麼嗎？因為你的媽媽明確的知道坎佈拉是什麼樣子
You know too.
你也知道
If you are looking for a wrong doing, it is the Kambura itself.
如果你想知道到底是誰的錯，那就是坎佈拉本身
Look mister, it is flying.
先生你看，飛起來了
It may even be so that...
甚至可能是這樣……
you're telling the truth Yeliz.
你說的是真相
You really have been raped.
你真的被強奸了
Yes, why not?
是的，為什麼不是？
Yesterday you were talking about everything in detail.
昨天你在談論細節的時候
But you avoided the subject of rape. Why?
你回避了強奸的問題，為什麼？
Because you couldn't do it.
因為你做不到
You had the guts to lie to us.
你有膽量騙我們
But you never had the courage to tell what happened to you.
但是你從來冇有勇氣告訴你發生了什麼
You really have been raped Yeliz.
你是真的被強奸了  耶利茲
Mrs Feza, it is flying.
費紮夫人  飛起來了
We finally did it. It's flying.
我們終於做到了
Mrs Feza!
費紮夫人！
It's flying.
飛起來了
And then, you married the man who raped you.
然後，你嫁給了強奸你的男人
Why? Because the place called Kambura never left you with another choice.
為什麼？因為這個叫做坎佈拉的地方給了你另一種選擇
That's what happened, isn't it?
就是這樣，不是嗎？
Come on, say it. Isn't that what happened?
來，說吧  那不是真相嗎？
That's enough Nevra. Leave the girl alone.
夠了 內芙拉  別說了
Because you've got nothing to say.
因為你無話可說
It means that it's not Tayyar who did this to you.
這意味著塔亞爾冇有對你做過任何事情
He might've done it to somebody else, but not to you.
他可能對別人做了，但不是對你
But why are you lying, blaming him?
但是你為什麼說謊，把責任推給他？
Is that what you want to believe?
這就是你想要相信的嗎?
Who do you think you're fooling? Yourself or us?
你認為自己是在欺騙誰？騙自己還是騙我們？
Do you think your husband will get away with it if you point the finger at Tayyar?
你認為如果你把矛頭指嚮塔亞爾，你的丈夫會逃脫懲罰嗎?
I'll tell you what, you can blame all the men in the world...
我告訴你，你可以責怪世界上所有的男人……
but it doesn't clear off your husband.
但這並不能給你丈夫脫罪
I am off to Kambura. Are you coming?
我要去坎佈拉  你來嗎？
Sure I am.
當然
You can tag along too, since your job is to spy on us.
你也可以跟蹤我們，因為你的工作就是監視我們
Don't bother, we'll meet you there.
坎佈拉見
It got stuck.
卡住了
The kite got stuck.
風吹被卡住了
Mrs Feza...
費紮夫人
the kite...
風吹
Mrs Feza!
費紮夫人
The kite got stuck.
風吹被卡住了
Poor Agah.
可憐的阿加
That's exactly what you'll become.
你就要變成這樣了
Never mind.
無所謂了
- Hello Ate?. - Nevra, where are you?
-你好阿提斯  -內芙拉，你在哪裏？
I am off to Kambura.
我要去坎佈拉
I was about to ask you to come to Kambura.
我正想讓你也一起來呢
Is that where you are?
你在那裏嗎？
I discovered this place when I first came to Istanbul.
我第一次來伊斯坦佈爾時發現了這個地方
When I was a student.
那時我還是個學生
I became a regular customer.
就成為了這裏的常客
Do you like it? Nice isn't it?
你喜歡嗎？
Yes, it is nice but...
是的，很好，但是……
how about the guys?
這些人是幹嘛的？
They are on duty.
他們在工作
I don't like going around in herds either.
我也不喜歡成群結隊
But I am being stalked by a psychopath. You saw it.
但是我被一個精神病纏住了，你看到了
You even saw him better than me.
你甚至比我看的更清楚
What am I supposed to do?
我應該做些什麼？
Change your routine until they arrest the man.
改變習慣，直到他們逮捕了那個兇手
I had a routine until that man began messing with my life.
在那個男人開始攪亂我的生活之前，我一直都是這樣
If you ask me what paradise is like...
如果你問天堂是什麼樣的……
I'd say "it is a place where every day is the same".
我會說“是一個每天都一樣的地方”
Where nothing changes, including me...
一切都冇有改變，包括我
a place where everything runs smooth.
一切順利的地方
As a matter of fact, I built such a place and lived there.
事實上，我建了這樣一個地方並住在那裏
Now, there is a devil in my paradise.
現在，有一個魔鬼在我的天堂
Do you want me to close down my paradise because of him?
你要我因為他而關閉我的天堂嗎？
And now, there is an angel there too.
現在，那裏也有天使
In this case...
在這種情況下
Mr Cemil...
塞米爾先生
is it coincidence that the devil and the angel made their way into your...
惡魔和天使同時闖入你的天堂
paradise simultaneously?
難道是巧合嗎？
have invaded?
是受邀而來？
Or was it fate?
還是命運？
I don't know that much but I must've left the door open...
我不太了解，但我必須把門打開
allowing both the devil and the angel in.
讓他們都進來
This is not the place.
不是這裏
Why did I come here?
我為什麼來這裏？
This is the place...
這個地方……
where an old friend used to live. His name is Nazif.
曾經住著我的老朋友納齊夫
Now he calls himself "Naz".
現在他自稱“納茲”
It's O.K I suppose. No harm in it.
冇關係，我認為冇關係
I once did something here.
我曾經在這裏做過一些事
They say the killer always returns to the scene of murder.
他們說，兇手總是回到謀殺現場
So did I.
我也是
I was supposed to forget about it.
我本該忘記的這個的
Wait a minute, your daughter is not here, is she?
等一下，你女兒不在這裏  對吧？
We can go to your place. There are no cameras there.
我們可以去你家了  那裏冇有監控
The house is empty.
房子是空的
I can play flamenco for you.
我可以為你演奏弗拉門戈舞
Olé!
奧萊！
Yes, sure. Olé.
是的，奧萊
- How did you find out? - I wanted to see the place.
-你怎麼知道的？-我想看看這個地方
A man hung himself, causing havoc in the town.
一名男子上吊自殺，給鎮子造成破壞
I came to check it out. And this is the situation.
我來看一看  然後就這樣了
As you can see, the place has gone back in time.
如你所見，房子已經不複存在了
There is nothing left. They covered it with earth, buried it completely.
他們什麼也冇剩下  用泥土完全掩埋了
I wonder who did it?
我想知道是誰做的？
I found out that too.
那個我也知道了
Havran Holding.
哈夫蘭控股
They bought the land from a farmer two years ago.
他們兩年前從農民手裏買了這塊土地
Havran Holding.
哈夫蘭控股
They have foundations, granting scholarship to children.
他們有基金會，為孩子們提供獎學金
Cemil Havran is the CEO.
塞米爾·哈夫蘭是執行長
And he is from Kambura.
他來自坎佈拉
Cemil.
塞米爾
Yes, we will build a hospital there. What is your name please?
是的，我們將在那裏建立醫院。請問你叫什麼名字？
Nevra Elmas.
內芙拉·埃爾瑪斯
Mrs Nesrin's daughter.
內斯林夫人的女兒
Of course I know her.
我當然認識她
Where from? Kambura of course.
怎麼認識的？當然是在坎佈拉認識的
Do you have any more questions Miss Nevra?
你還有其他疑問嗎？
Yes, I have.
是的，我有
What made you knock this building down after all these years?
過了這麼多年  是什麼原因使你拆掉了這房子？
-Especially right after... -Yes. Right after a sad incident.
-尤其是在……-在那場悲劇之後
And I knew Ufuk very well.
我非常了解烏福克
Sad.
我很傷心
May he rest in peace.
願他安息
Look Miss Nevra, you can be called a native of Kambura.
聽著，內芙拉小姐，你也可以被稱為坎佈拉人
Kambura is a significant place for me.
坎佈拉對我來說是重要的地方
A life has vanished there.
一條生命在那裏結束了
We decided to do something that would pave way for other lives to flourish.
我們決定做一些事情，為其他生命的繁榮鋪平道路
Do you understand?
你理解嗎？
That's why we decided to build a hospital.
這就是為什麼我們決定建一家醫院
I tell you what we can do...
我告訴你我們能做什麼
make an appointment with me...
找個時間見一麵
we sit down and a have nice chat over a nice cup of coffee.
我們坐下來聊天愉快，喝杯咖啡
By the way, this is my private number.
順便說一句，這是我的私人電話
You're with the police force.
你是警察
Therefore you had no problem of obtaining my number.
因此，你毫無疑問能夠獲得我的電話號碼
But, don't call me on this number again.
但是，不要再給我打電話這個號碼
In fact, it is better if you forget this number.
實際上，最好忘記這個號碼
It is best if you delete it from your contacts list.
最好將其從聯係人列錶中刪除
But if it's too much trouble for you, I get in touch with your bosses...
但如果你給我造成了太多麻煩，我會與你的老闆聯係
and they can do it for you.
他們可以幫你
Is it O.K?
好嗎？
Give my regards to your mother.
代我嚮你母親緻意
Stupid girl.
愚蠢的女孩
She's gone into all that trouble to find your number...
她費了很大勁才找到你的電話號碼
to talk about this.
就為了問這事情
Let's not say "stupid"...
我們不要說“愚蠢”
let's say "enthusiastic".
可以說“熱情”
Young.
年輕
Never ran into a wall.
從來冇碰過壁
They broke it again.
他們又把它弄壞了
They broke the lock Mrs Feza.
他們把門鎖弄壞了  費紮夫人
It is O.K now.
現在可以了
The locksmith had said that they follow your moves.
鎖匠曾說過他們會跟隨你的行動
They broke in when they realized that the house was empty.
當他們知道到房子裏麵冇人的時候，他們會闖進來
Isn't that right?
是不是？
I checked the place. Not much damage. I don't think they took anything.
我查過了冇什麼損害  我不認為他們拿走了任何東西
The bedroom is a little messy. But apart from that...!
但除此之外臥室有點淩亂……！
There is supposed to be a fish there. I wonder if it's still alive.
那裏應該有一條魚  我想知道它是否還活著
Did it have a name?
它有名字嗎？
Did the fish have a name Mrs Feza?
魚的名字叫菲紮太太嗎？
What did you name it?
你給它起了什麼名字？
What would I name it if it was me?
如果是我，我怎麼稱呼它？
Agah?
阿加？
Yes?
是？
You killed Mehmet.
你殺了穆罕默德
They say Mrs Feza was kidnapped.
他們說費紮夫人被綁架了
I reported it to the police. They are looking for her.
我已經報警了  警察在找她
I told them what happened to her husband.
我告訴警察她丈夫發生了什麼
They say it probably has nothing to do with it.
他們說這可能與之無關
They know nothing. Cops are useless.
他們什麼都不知道  警察真冇用
Finally! I have been trying to get hold of you since morning.
終於接電話了！從早上以來我一直試圖聯係你
I know dad. I am sorry. It's been such a hectic day.
我知道爸爸  很抱歉  今天很忙
I am still busy. But you can talk to me if it's emergency.
我還是很忙  但如果有緊急情況你可以和我談談
Do you remember the judge, Mehmet Yurtgil?
你還記得法官穆罕默德·尤爾吉爾嗎？
His wife Feza was staying here. They kidnapped her.
他的妻子費紮住在這裏   有人綁架了她
Kidnapped? Who? When?
綁架了？什麼時候？
This morning, during the stroll in the park.
今天早上，在公園散步時
They say she got lost. But I am sure she was kidnapped...
他們說她迷路了  但是我確定她是被綁架了
by her husband's killer.
被殺她丈夫的殺手
They reported it to the police. But the police is not doing anything.
他們嚮警察報告了，但是警察冇有做任何事情
Why would they kidnap her? She was very ill.
他為什麼要綁架她？她病得很重。
I think they kidnap her to stop her telling the story.
我認為他綁架她是為了讓她閉嘴
She may reveal what she witnessed to.
她可能會透露自己目睹的事情
You can't trust human brain. You can never know how it works.
你不能相信人類的大腦  你永遠不知道它是如何運作的
Would you take the risk if you were the murderer?
如果你是兇手，你會冒險嗎？
Moreover, Mrs Feza had begun to talk recently.
而且，費紮夫人最近開始說話了
What was she saying?
她在說什麼
She was reading poems?
她是在讀詩嗎？
I see.
我懂了
To the space?
去太空？
I've got it, dad. I'll take care of it.
我知道了，爸爸，我會處理的
Don't worry, I'll take care of it.
不用擔心，我會處理的
What's going on? Who kidnapped who?
這是怎麼回事？誰綁架了誰？
Feza Yurtgil, Mehmet Yurtgil's wife.
費紮·尤爾吉爾，穆罕默德·尤爾吉爾的妻子
She suffers from Alzheimer's Disease.
她患有阿爾茨海默氏病
She's gone missing in the park.
她在公園裏失蹤了
By the way, Naz?m Hikmet travelled to space but police didn't know about it.
另外，納茲姆·希克梅特去了太空，但警方對此一無所知
Let's go.
我們走吧
Unfortunately, we are closed to the press.
但是，我們不接受媒體採訪
He will find out anyway.
反正他會查出來的
The anonymous tipper among us will tell him everything.
我們中間的告密者會告訴他一切
Now or later, what is the difference?
現在或以後，有什麼區別？
You are not the ones who should be ashamed.
你們不是應該感到羞恥的人
The ones who see you as an item to be bought and sold...
那些將你們視為商品的人
they are the ones who should be ashamed.
他們才是應該感到羞恥的人
What did they teach us?
他們教了我們什麼？
Complete the opposite.
完成相反的
You've got raped because you've wagged your tail.
你被強奸了，因為你搖了搖尾巴
You got harassed on the street because you revealed your body too much.
你在街上受到騷擾，因為你的身體暴露得太多了
So many young girls walking bent-over in Kambura...
那麼多年輕女孩在坎佈拉彎著腰走路……
to hide their breasts from men.
為了嚮男人們隱藏她們的胸部
Are you aware of it?
你知道嗎？
The hump on children's back...
童子背上的駝??峰
is our fault.
是我們的錯
Mebrule used to hold the cardigan against my back to measure it.
梅佈魯雷以前用開襟衫靠在我的背上進行測量。
I am taking over from she left off.
她過身後我接手了
I wish she was here so I could knit something for her.
我希望她還在，那樣我可以為她編織一些東西
But it is too dark to see in here.
但是這裏太黑了
I am sorry Mrs Feza. We are left in the dark.
抱歉，費紮太太  我們被睏在黑暗中
But we had to do it to stop others seeing what's going on inside.
但是我們必須這樣做，以防其他人看到裏麵發生了什麼
The door can't be locked.
門不能鎖
You can't even shut it properly, let alone locking it.
甚至都關不上，更不用說鎖門了
Mr Münir used to hate the doors too.
穆尼爾曾經也很討厭門
Mr Münir, my cat.
穆尼爾先生，我的貓
He hated closed doors.
他討厭關門
He used to tap it with his paw, asking me to open it.
他曾經用爪子敲它，要我打開它
But he was so exhausted in his final days.
但是他在最後的日子非常疲憊
He was unable get up.
他無法起床
He was unable to get up to even ask for water.
他甚至無法起床  無法要水喝
And I never realized.
我從來冇有意識到
So intriguing.
如此有趣
This...
這個
look.
看
Guide to Documentation Sorting.
文檔分類指南
I have this book too.
我也有這本書
This man.
這個人
His name is Tayyar Kaymak.
他的名字叫塔亞爾·凱馬克
He raped a girl in Kambura sometime between 10 and 15 years ago.
他在10到15年前在坎佈拉強奸了一個女孩
We don't know how old she was at the time.
我們不知道她當時多大
But she is an adult woman now.
但是她現在是成年女性
Ladies, I am looking for this woman.
女士們，我在找這個女人
Please come forward if you know anything about this woman...
如果你對這個女人有任何線索，請挺身而出
about this incident or about Tayyar Kaymak.
無論是關於這個女人還是關於塔亞爾
Believe me, the smallest of information you provide will save a life.
相信我，你提供的信息將能夠挽救生命
Please, come forward if you know anything.
拜托，如果你知道什麼，請挺身而出
Don't hide it.
不要隱瞞
Don't hide it, so the woman wouldn't have to hide anymore.
不要隱瞞它，這樣女人就不必再隱藏了
The book has it all.
這本書講了一切
How to sort documentation.
如何分類文件
There are many ways.
有很多方法
One of them is...
其中之一是
by numbering each letter.
通過給每個字母編號
For example 1 for A, 2 for B, 3 for C and so on.
例如，A代錶1，B代錶2，C代錶3，依此類推。
And then...
接著……
yes, I always sort my documents this way.
是的，我總是以這種方式對文件進行排序
I never forgot.
我從未忘記
When you see the number...
當你看到數字
1682.
Mrs Feza, 1682.
費紮夫人，1682
1 is A.
1是A
No, it said "1682 is the combination for the Flat No:8".
不，上麵寫著“ 1682是8號公寓的密碼組合”
If there is No:8, 1682 refers to something else.
如果有8號公寓，則1682是指其他事情
So, it is not 1, It is 16.
所以不是1，而是16
If it's 16...
如果是16
A, B, C, ?, D, E...
A，B，C，?，D，E
M.
M
Mebrule.
梅佈魯雷
You can call me on this number anytime.
你可以隨時撥打此電話
All I want is to find that woman.
我隻想找到那個女人
If someone did that to me, ruining my dignity...
如果有人對我這樣做，破壞我的尊嚴……
I would commit suicide.
我會自殺
What did you say?
你說什麼？
Yes, you.
是的，就是你
I said nothing.
我什麼都冇說
Yes, you did. You said if it happened to you...
是的，你說如果這件事發生在你身上……
I said I would commit suicide. Wouldn't you?
我說過要自殺  不是嗎？
A man rapes you and you carry on living?
一個男人強奸了你，你會繼續生活嗎？
Who can bear it?
誰能承受？
How can you face your loved ones?
你怎麼能麵對親人？
How can you go back home, to your family?
你怎麼能回家告訴你的親人呢？
Mebrule Blocks.
梅佈魯雷區
I've got it Mrs Feza. Mebrule Blocks.
我知道了費紮夫人
Flat no: 8. But what is the "2" at the end?
8號公寓  但是最後的“ 2”是什麼？
Mebrule Blocks, flat no: 8.
梅佈魯雷區  8號公寓
16, 8, 2, B.
16、8、2，B
Beyo?lu.
貝約魯
Agah, Beyo?lu.
阿加·貝尤魯
Mebrule Blocks, flat 8, Beyo?lu. I've got it.
梅佈魯雷區，第8單元公寓，貝尤魯大樓  我知道了
Mrs Feza, I found the house.
費紮夫人，我找到了房子
I found the address. Get up.
我找到地址  起來吧
Get up, we are going home.
起來，我們要回家了
Mrs Feza, I've got it. Come on.
費紮太太，我知道了
Let's go back to the station. We'll check the archives.
我們回局裏查檔案
To look for what?
尋找什麼？
Suicides committed in the last 15 years...
最近15年的自殺事件
and we'll go back 20 years if necessary.
如果需要的話，我們回溯20??年
Because the girl committed suicide.
因為那個女孩自殺了
The girl whom Tayyar raped committed suicide.
塔亞爾強奸的那個女孩自殺了
That's why we can't find her.
這就是為什麼我們找不到她
Because she is no longer alive.
因為她已經死了
We've got the address. How could I not remember it?
我們有地址的  我怎麼就不記得了？
Just a minute, let me put the book back in its place.
請等一下，讓我將書本放回原處
Yes.
好了
Mrs Feza.
費紮夫人
Flamenco?
弗拉明戈？
- Olé. - Sure, Olé.
-奧萊-當然，奧萊
Well, well, well...
好吧好吧
the honourable D.A, I can see you're having a good time.
尊敬的檢察官先生，我可以看到你玩的很愉快
I am sorry to interrupt but we have to talk.
很抱歉打擾，但我們不得不談談
How did you know I was here?
你怎麼知道我在這裏？
How did I know?
我怎麼知道？
I have as many informants as officers in my team.
我的團隊裏有很多線人
They tell me everything.
他們告訴我一切
Where you go, what time you finish work.
你去哪裏，什麼時候完成工作
They tell me everything.
他們告訴我一切
What do you want?
你想要什麼？
Now, the honourable D.A...
現在，尊敬的檢察官
who has been messing with my case and why?
是誰一直在糾纏我的案子，為什麼？
This is number one.
這是第一個問題
And the number two...
還有第二個……
who specifically reinstated the man to the case...
是誰特別指定菲魯茲
whom I removed.
恢複到案件調查中
Who is running this case? What's going on?
誰在插手此案？怎麼回事？
Look, a little advice from me...
聽著，我給你一些建議
do you know the secret to move up in the ladder?
你知道升官的秘訣嗎？
Not to ask questions.
不問問題
F... ck the ladder.
去尼瑪的升官
I don't want to move up anywhere. How about that?
我一點都不想往上爬  行不行？
Not moving up means you are stuck where you are.
不往上爬意味著你會被睏在原地
And that's where you'll be buried.
那就是你被埋葬的地方
Are you threatening me?
你在威脅我嗎
No, just talking about a simple rule of management.
不，隻是談論管理的簡單規則
Rule of management. I like that.
我喜歡這樣的管理規則
For a moment, I thought you were threatening me.
有那麼一瞬間，我以為你在威脅我
Because I am allergic to it. It gives me the itch.
因為我對威脅過敏所以很癢
When someone threatens me I threaten them back.
當有人威脅我時 我會威脅回去
Now, talking about threats...
現在，說到威脅……
does your beautiful and respected wife know what you are up to here?
你美麗而受人尊敬的妻子知道你在這裏做什麼嗎？
You are a good man Tolga. You wouldn't do such a thing.
你是是個好人  托爾加  你不會做這樣的事情
You haven't got the evil in you.
你內心冇有邪惡
That's right. I haven't got the evil.
是的，我冇有邪惡
But when I walk out that door anything can happen.
但是當我走出去那扇門  什麼都有可能會發生
You never know what a man is capable of doing.
你永遠不知道人有多大能耐
Mankind is an unpredictable species.
人類是不可預測的物種
I don't know who gave the orders.
我不知道是誰的命令
They called both from Ministry of Internal Affairs and Ministry of Justice.
他們分別聯係了內政部和法務部
They told me what to do and I agreed.
他們告訴我該怎麼做，我隻是執行
I swear, I don't know who is pulling the strings.
我發誓，我不知道是誰在發號施令
You won't say anything to anyone, will you?
你不會對別人說什麼，對嗎？
Everybody has a soft belly.
每個人都有弱點
Being lured by temptations depends on the one's personality.
能否被誘惑吸引取決於一個人的人格
And that's your problem. It has nothing to do with me.
那是你的問題  與我無關
Have fun.
玩得開心
You are great Mrs Feza. You really are.
你跳得太好了  費紮夫人  真的太好了
You were great.
你很棒
Come on, let's not keep the children waiting.
來吧，不要讓孩子們等著
Shall we go now?
我們現在可以走了嗎？
O.K, one more.
好  再跳一首麯子
This is the last one.
這是最後一個
Just a minute. Let's do it properly.
等一下  讓我們好好跳
Ladies and gentlemen...
女士們先生們……
greatest name of all times of flamenco dance.
弗拉門戈舞蹈史上最偉大的舞者
A unique talent...
一位特殊的天才……
Senora Feza.
塞諾拉·費薩
[Cause of Death: Suicide.
[死亡原因：自殺]
Mrs Feza?
費紮夫人？
What happened?
發生了什麼？？
What happened? Are you alright?
怎麼了？你還好嗎？
Can you hear me?
你能聽到我嗎？
Mrs Feza?
費紮夫人？
Please, don't do this.
拜托不要這樣
This can't be happening.
這不可能
Please.
不要啊
Can you hear me Mrs Feza?
你能聽到我費紮夫人嗎？
Please, don't. Don't do this.
拜托，不要這樣
Please, no.
請不要
I was going to take you home.
我本打算要帶你回家
I was going to cook for you.
我本打算要為你做飯
I was going to knit a jumper for you.
我本打算要為你編織一件毛衣
I was going to look after you.
我本打算要照顧你的
I was unable to look after Mebrule. But I was going to look after you.
我無法照顧梅佈魯雷，但是我要照顧你
I wasn't going to be like Mr Mehmet. I was never going to moan.
我不會像穆罕默德先生那樣  我永遠不會抱怨
I was going to look after you.
我本打算要照顧你的
I thought of everything.
我把一切都計畫好了
I was going to introduce you to my daughter.
我本打算把你介紹給我的女兒
I was going to introduce you to my grandchild.
我本打算把你介紹給我的孫子
I was going to say "Look, this is Mrs Feza."
我要說：“看，這是費紮太太”
"She is a dear old friend of mine".
“她是我的親愛的老朋友”
"She is not well". "She is staying in a nursing home".
“她不舒服”“她住在療養院”
"But she is lonely and unhappy there". "From now on, she'll be staying with us."
“但是她在那裏感到孤獨和不快樂”“從現在開始，她將和我們住在一起”
"She'll be forever staying with us".
“她將永遠和我們在一起”
Please, don't do this.
拜托不要這樣
This can't be happening.
這不可能
Olé, Olé, Olé.
奧萊！奧萊！奧萊！
[Hi Deva, I am the "Dog Killer".
[嗨，德瓦，我是“狗殺手”]
[F... ck off!
[滾開！]
[You don't believe me.] [But this little gift may convince you.]
[你不相信我] [但是這個小禮物可能會說服你]
- Are you going out? - I'll be right back.
-你要出去嗎？-我馬上回來
Nevra!
內芙拉！
Wait!
等等！
Nevra!
內芙拉！
Are you alright?
你還好嗎？
Reyhan.
雷漢
What?
什麼？
Reyhan committed suicide.
雷漢自殺了
Who is Reyhan?
誰是雷漢？
Don't tell anybody, O.K?
不要告訴任何人，好嗎？
You promised Nevra. Don't forget.
你嚮我保證   內芙拉  不要忘記
O.K, I won't forget.
好，我不會忘記